Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
The hypothetical became reality.
Talk about unlucky, the proponent
becoming the test subject herself.
Then, that contact experiment
was the direct cause?
Mental breakdown, that was
the result of the contact.
But how cruel is it to commit suicide,
leaving such a young daughter behind?
No, there might actually be
more to this than that.
Asuka, dear, your mom cooked
your favorite dish today.
Come on, if you're picky about your food,
that big girl over there is going to laugh at you.
She goes on like that every day.
She talks to the doll, thinking it's her daughter.
She probably feels responsible in her own way.
Her research filled her days and she had no time
to pay attention to our daughter.
You have my sympathies.
But the way she is, they're
practically a family of dolls.
No, perhaps humans and dolls
are not so different.
Humans made dolls in their own image.
If God exists, we may be nothing more
than dolls to Him.
I'm surprised to hear such words from
a practitioner of modern medicine.
I'm just another human before I'm a doctor,
a flesh and blood woman.
You're such a good girl, Asuka.
It's okay, you don't have to hold it in, you know?
It's okay. I'm not going to cry.
I'm going to think for myself.
Can you hear me, Asuka?
Your synch rate is down by eight points.
As always, keep your mind off other things.
I'm doing it!
EPISODE 22
AT LEAST, BE HUMAN
Asuka's synch rate has been
on a downward trend lately.
It's problematic, considering our tight situation.
Let's make Rei's Unit 00 our priority.
Right now, we don't have the leeway
to repair both at the same time.
Mitosis in Unit 02's left arm has
cleared the target value.
Necrosis is currently under
point zero five percent.
The apoptosis process is operating normally.
Unit 00's morphogenetic system
is currently stable.
Please connect receptors to Signal 2.
The Eva series, born from Adam.
We even have to make use of what
caused the Second Impact
in order for us to win against the Angels.
Put it another way, in order to live,
we will even use the thing
that tried to wipe us out.
I guess that's what humans do.
In the end, maybe I do hate the Eva.
My father's murderer...
Miss Katsuragi!
Construction of Evas up through
Unit 13 has begun?
In seven different locations around the world?
This information came via Shanghai.
The source can be trusted.
Why are they rushing mass production
at this stage?
We've lost two Evas in the past and
two are currently heavily damaged.
Perhaps they're rushing
to reinforce our reserves
with an eye towards the
secondary preparations.
I don't know.
Even here, we're getting Germany
to give us pans
from Unit 05 and 06 that are
being built there.
There seems to be a lot of money
changing hands lately.
Our budget was doubled since
we came here after all.
Do you suppose that just shows
how desperate the higher-ups are?
I sense a certain impatience on
the part of the Committee.
Then are they anticipating a case
where not single,
but multiple Angels are deployed
against us at once?
Maybe, but there's no reason to do it unofficially.
They must have some other objective in mind.
All three of us are here for once
and we're just so awkward.
I'm done.
Asuka!
No way! It's just going to be
another call from Kaji for you!
You answer it!
That's not likely.
Oh, my, the great invincible Shinji,
lowering himself to such a menial chore.
Thank you so very much.
Yes, hello?
What's with his prissy attitude?
An international call from Germany for you.
It's your mother.
For me? From Mom?
Give it here!
When she's talking in a language
I don't understand,
it's like she becomes a total stranger.
A mother?
You sure talked for a long time.
Well, it's our usual bit of communication.
It must be nice to have a family to talk to.
Well, just in appearance. It's only on the surface.
She's not my real mother anyway.
But it's not like I hate her.
I just don't deal with her well.
Why the hell am I telling you all this?!
Sorry.
It's all over if even you start
sympathizing with me!
She's at negative twelve point eight
on the synch index,
just barely above the activation level.
That's terrible.
She's dropped off even more than yesterday.
Asuka isn't feeling well today.
She's on her second day.
The synch rate isn't affected by
superficial physical conditions.
The problem lies more in the subconscious.
We may have no choice but to
change the core of Unit 02.
Asuka, you can come up.
Repair work on Power Grid 8 is scheduled to begin at 1800 today.
Asuka's pride is in pieces.
The regular meeting concerning the disposal issue
It's not surprising, considering how she lost.
Of Command Center 1 will be held on schedule.
Or rather, the fact she thinks she lost to Shinji looms larger.
General Affairs managers, please come
to Conference Room 2.
Maybe the three of us living together has reached the limit.
Threshold exceeded?
Is this the end of your merry game of house?
I don't want to hear that from someone who keeps a cat to keep loneliness at bay.
I'm sorry, I guess I'm on edge.
Why do I have to go through this just
because I'm a woman?!
I don't even want kids!
Route Loop 7 is currently closed
due to an accident.
Please use the detour via Route 12.
The Eva won't move unless you open your heart.
Are you saying that my heart is closed?!
Yes, the Evas have souls.
Those puppets?!
You should know that.
Fancy you starting up a conversation!
Maybe it'll snow tomorrow!
What?! Are you so happy that
I can't pilot my Eva?!
There's nothing to worry about!
If another Angel attacks us,
the great, invincible Shinji will
take care of it for us!
We don't have to do anything!
All they need is Shinji!
First, I get Shinji's sympathy, and now,
even from the mechanical puppet girl.
I've really lost my edge.
I am not a puppet.
Shut up! You do whatever you're told!
You'd die if Commander Ikari
told you to, wouldn't you?!
That's right.
You really ARE a puppet!
I've always really hated you because
you're so much like a puppet!
Everyone! I hate everyone!
Shinji didn't show up today either.
Though Ayanami's absence is normal.
Asuka didn't come either.
And Suzuhara's still in the hospital.
I guess school isn't much of a priority right now.
Signal from Eva Unit 02 showing no problems.
VA connection and fusion are normal.
Rate of proliferation is within expected limits.
You're my puppet, so all you have to do
is quietly do as I say!
Why does a weapon need a soul anyway?!
It only gets in the way!
Anyway, all you have to do is obey my orders.
This is so stupid.
All hands, battle stations, level one!
Prepare for anti-air combat!
An Angel?! They're still coming?!
Angel, visually confirmed.
Here is the highest magnification.
It isn't budging from its satellite orbit.
It's maintaining a set distance from our location.
Which means, it's waiting for a chance
to descend and close in,
or it can attack us without the need to do so.
We can't make a careless move at this rate.
Either way, we can't do anything about it
unless the target moves within our firing range.
The Eva units aren't capable of
attacking anything in orbit.
How's Rei?
She's in good shape, along with Unit 00.
She's ready to go.
Roger that.
Launch Unit 00!
Prepare for extreme long range firing.
Unit 02 and Asuka will stand by
for launch as backup!
Backup?! Me?! To Unit 00?!
That's right, take the rear position.
You have got to be joking!
Eva Unit 02, taking off!
Asuka!
That's fine, we'll let her take the lead.
Major Katsuragi!
Meaning, this is the end for Asuka
if she can't perform now.
Her last chance, then?
We'll have to think about
a replacement pilot for Unit 02.
Yes, Ma'am.
Aren't we sending out Unit 01?
It's been put on suspension under
Commander Ikari's strict orders.
I suppose it's not surprising
after what happened.
INSPECTION
DIVISION
If I mess this up, they'll probably
take me off Unit 02.
No mistakes allowed, Asuka.
Target is still outside firing range.
Oh, hurry up and get over here already!
Talk about irritating!
WARNING
Is it a direct energy weapon?!
No, I'm not getting any thermal energy readings.
Her psychograph readings are agitated!
Mental contamination beginning!
The Angel is launching a psychological attack?
They can comprehend the mind
of a human being?
Goddamn it!
Positrons have dissipated!
No good! It's outside the firing range!
Unit 02, out of rifle ammunition!
Analysis of the ray of light?!
It's an energy wave within the visible spectrum!
It's similar to the AT Field,
but details are unknown!
What about Asuka?
She's in danger! The mental
contamination has entered Y!
No!
Don't... Don't come inside me!
It hurts
It hurts!
Don't come in!
Stop it
Don't come inside
No!
It hurts
MOTHER
No!
Don't look inside my mind!
Please! Don't dig deeper into my heart!
Asuka!
Her psychograph readings are at their limit!
Her mental circuits are being torn to shreds.
It'll be too dangerous if they're
overloaded any more.
Asuka, come back!
No!
That's an order! Asuka, retreat!
No! Never!
I'd rather die here than go back now!
Asuka!
Accelerator being aligned.
Voltage increasing, approaching pressurization.
Forced convergence, activated.
Adjusting zero point zero three
for Earth's rotation and gravity.
Superconductive guidance system in operation.
Chamber at maximum pressure.
Final safety released!
Release confirmed.
Everything in launch position!
It's no good! The power level is far too low
to penetrate the AT Field at this range!
But output is at maximum! Anything more is...
Unit 02, psychograph readings
are growing weaker!
What about the LCL's psychological barrier?!
It's no use. It's not even working as a catalyst!
Prioritize life support. Shut out
the feedback from the Eva.
Yes, Ma'am.
It's as if this light is probing Asuka's
psychological wavelength.
Could it be that the Angel is trying
to learn about the human mind?!
Why am I crying?
I already decided I wouldn't cry anymore.
What's the matter, Asuka?
It's a present from your new mom.
Don't you like it?
It's okay.
What's okay?
I'm not a child!
I'm going to grow up quickly.
I don't need stuffed animals.
So look at me!
Mom! Please, don't quit being my mom!
Die with me.
Mom! Mom! Please don't kill me!
No! I'm not your doll!
I'm going to think and live for myself!
I don't need a mom or a dad.
I'm going to live on my own.
No, don't make me remember this!
I'd forgotten about it! Don't dig it up again!
I don't need any of this bad stuff anymore!
Stop it already! Stop it!
My mind's been defiled.
Mr. Kaji, I've been defiled.
What will I do? I've been defiled.
Unit 02 has shut down!
Life support has developed a problem.
Pilot entering a dangerous state!
No change in target.
Relative distance has remained the same.
Probability of it moving within firing range
of Unit 00 is point zero two percent.
Should we transport Unit 00 into the air
and snipe it from there?
No, that won't work.
It'll all be over if we get shot down
on the approach.
I'll go out there in Unit 01!
No! The target corrodes the pilot's psyche.
Fight now, we must avoid
the. corrosion oi Unit 01.
Then I just have to keep from getting hit, right?!
Your success is not guaranteed.
But at this rate, Asuka will...
I don't care. Rei, go down into Dogma
and use the Lance.
The Lance of Longinus?!
Ikari, that is...
We cannot reach the target's AT Field in orbit,
and that's the only way to bring it down.
Hurry!
But contact between an Eva and Adam
might cause the Third Impact!
It's far too dangerous!
Commander Ikari, please don't do this!
A lie, so it was a deception.
Contact with an Angel was not the cause
of the Second Impact then.
Central Dogma, levels ten to fifteen
have been unlocked.
Unit 00 has passed through
the sixth trench of the Malebolge.
Levels sixteen to twenty
have now been unlocked.
So the Third Impact won't happen.
At least, not because of this.
Then what caused the Second Impact?
Ikari, are we not getting ahead of ourselves?
The Committee has already started
mass-producing the Eva series.
This is our chance, Fuyutsuki.
But this is...
We cannot turn back time,
but we do have the power to spur it onward.
The old men will not stand for this!
We must finish everything before
Seele begins to act.
It would be unwise for us
to lose Unit 02 right now.
That may be, but using the Lance of Longinus
without Seele's permission will be troublesome.
A reason need only exist.
Anything beyond that is insignificant.
A reason? What you're looking for
is an excuse, isn't it?
Brain waves of Unit 02 pilot have
dropped to zero point zero six!
Life support reaching a critical point!
Unit 00 has passed through Number 2,
emerging on surface.
So, that's the Lance of Longinus.
Unit 00, prepared to throw.
Target confirmed. Adjustment for errors made.
Beginning countdown.
T-minus ten seconds.
Eight...
Seven...
Six...
Five...
Four...
Three...
Two...
One...
Zero!
Target has been destroyed.
Eva Unit 02 disengaged.
What about the Lance of Longinus?
It broke the first astronautical velocity.
It is currently moving into lunar orbit.
Recovering it will be nearly impossible.
Yes, at present, we do not have the means
to bring back that much mass.
Unit 02 is in good condition.
Readings currently at normal levels.
Bring the Eva back to Cage 2.
Please use Route 67.
What about Asuka?
Pilot's life signs confirmed.
Quarantine due to the contamination
has been removed.
I see.
DO NOT ENTER
I'm glad for you, Asuka.
Shut up! There's nothing to be glad about!
Of all the people, she had to be
the one to save me!
I had to be saved by HER!
I would've rather died than be saved by her!
I hate it! I hate it! I hate everyone!
I hate everyone so much!
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
Eva Unit 00 is possessed
and violated by an Angel.
Rei chooses death of her own will in order
to protect Shinji from the Angel's corrosion.
She disappears along with New Tokyo-S,
turning into light and heat.
Next time: "Tears"
TEARS